realvision.com 2019-12-12

# Privacy Policy | Real Vision

UPDATED ON September 06, 2018

**Real Vision Group SEZC**  and its subsidiaries and affiliates (collectively, “Real Vision,” “we,” “us,” and “our”), want you to be familiar with how we collect, use and disclose information from and about you because we understand you are concerned about your privacy, and we want to maintain your trust.

This Privacy Policy applies to information we collect from all sources including in connection with our websites and mobile sites (each a “Site” and collectively the “Sites”), applications (“apps”), electronic newsletters and widgets (all such Sites, apps, newsletters and widgets being collectively referred to below as the “Services”) that link to this Privacy Policy.

This Policy describes Real Vision’s collection and use of users’ Personal Information. It also describes generally Real Vision’s practices for handling Other Information (e.g., interests, demographics and services usage, etc.) collected through the Real Vision Services. As described more fully below, we share information with our subsidiaries and third-party business partners (“Real Vision Affiliates”) for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy. By using the Real Vision Services or by providing personal information to us, you agree both to our Terms of Use (which are incorporated herein) and the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy.

You may choose not to submit requested information online (see Other Information below), but that may limit the services Real Vision is able to provide to you.

The Real Vision Services are a network of general audience sites, and are not targeted to, and do not knowingly collect Personal Information from, minors under 18 years of age. We request that these individuals do not provide Personal Information through the Real Vision Services.

#### 2\. Information We Collect 

Real Vision and our service providers may collect the following information from and about you:

 **2.1 Personal Information:**  “Personal Information” for purposes of this Privacy Policy is the information that identifies you as an individual or relates to an identifiable person, such as name, postal address (including billing and shipping addresses), telephone number, email address, credit or debit card number, or profile picture(s).

 **2.2 Personal Information That You Provide to Us:**  We collect Personal Information when, for example, you register for or subscribe to certain products or services from Real Vision Affiliates; create a profile; participate in a sweepstakes, contest or game; take a survey; visit our Real Vision Services; use any interactive features; participate in a community forum; or contact our customer service representatives through the messaging functionality made available to you on the Site and through the Services.

 **2.3 Personal Information We Receive from Third Parties:**  We may receive Personal Information about you from third parties, such as social media services, commercially available sources, Real Vision Affiliates, business partners, and, if applicable to you, the third-party provider of your subscription. The Personal Information we receive from third parties may include, for example, your name, contact information, information about your transactions, purchase history, or relationships with various product and service providers, and your use of certain applications. For example, if you access Real Vision Services through a social media service or connect the Real Vision Services to a social media service, the information we collect may also include your user name associated with that social media service, any information or content the social media service has the right to share with us, such as your profile picture, email address or friends list, and any information you have made public in connection with that social media service. When you access the Real Vision Services through social media services or when you connect the Real Vision Services to social media services, you are authorizing Real Vision to collect, store, and use such information and content in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

 **2.4 Other Information:**  “Other Information” is any information that does not reveal your specific identity, such as browser information, app usage data, information collected through cookies and other technologies, demographic information, and aggregated information.

 **2.5 Other Information You Submit:**  We collect Other Information when you submit it to us. It may include your gender, zip code, birthday, education, occupation, financial information (such as your income, investments, portfolio transactions and value, and other information), and interests.

 **2.6 Other Information We Receive from Third Parties:**  We may receive Other Information about you from third parties, including, for example, demographic data, social media account number, information about your interests, and information about your activities on other websites.

 **2.7 Other Information We Collect Automatically When You Are Online; Use of Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies:**  When you access and interact with our Real Vision Services, we and our service providers may automatically collect certain information about those visits. For example, in order to permit your connection to the Real Vision Services, our servers receive and record information about your computer, device, and browser, potentially including your IP address, browser type, and other software or hardware information. If you access the Real Vision Services from a mobile or other device, we may collect a unique device identifier assigned to that device (“UDID”), geolocation data, or other transactional information for that device.

Real Vision and our service providers also may use cookies and other tracking technologies (such as browser cookies, pixels, beacons, and Adobe Flash technology including cookies) when you visit or use the Real Vision Services. Third parties that support the Real Vision Services by serving advertisements or providing services, such as providing users with the ability to comment on content, allowing users to share content, customizing content based on usage, or tracking aggregate site usage statistics, may also use these technologies to collect Other Information on the Real Vision Services and on other websites.

The following is a list of the service providers that use cookies and other tracking technologies to analyze usage of the Site and Services, deliver and improve the Site, and to display relevant content, products, services and advertising. This list is not meant to be exhaustive and is subject to change at any time as we may engage the services of other providers to improve the Real Vision Services.

  * Intercom – customer support tool
  * Google Tag Manager – integration tool for analytics and conversion tracking
  * Google Analytics – web interaction analytics
  * Google AdWords – advertising campaign conversion tracking
  * HotJar – analytics & heat mapping
  * Facebook conversion tracking – advertising campaign conversion tracking
  * LinkedIn conversion tracking – advertising campaign conversion tracking
  * Twitter conversion tracking – advertising campaign conversion tracking

Our cookies:

  * Login token for identifying authenticated users. Called “token”
  * Features token for identifying multi-variety tests attached to user. Called “features”

Please note that no identifying data is stored in cookies. However, specific information about our users is sent to Google Tag Manager and Intercom (name and email address) in order to help with customer support.

By using the Site, you agree that we can use these technologies as described in this Privacy Policy.

Most browsers are initially set to accept cookies, but you can change your settings to notify you when a cookie is being set or updated, or to block cookies altogether. Please consult the “Help” section of your browser for more information.

You can manage the use of Flash technologies with the Flash management tools available at Adobe’s website, http://www.adobe.com/devnet/security.edu.html. Please note that by blocking any or all cookies you may not have access to certain features or personalization available through our Real Vision Services.

#### 3\. How we Use Your Information

We use the Personal Information we collect from and about you for the purposes set forth below. Please note that we may use and disclose Other Information for any purpose, except where we are required to do otherwise under applicable law. If we are required to treat Other Information as Personal Information under applicable law, then we may use and disclose it for all the purposes for which we use and disclose Personal Information. We may combine Other Information with your Personal Information, and when we do, we treat the combined information as Personal Information.

To improve the quality of our products and services and to personalize your experience by presenting content, products and offers tailored to you, we may also combine the Personal and Other Information we collect with information relating to your use of other Real Vision products, services and websites. In addition, we may supplement the Personal and Other Information we collect with information from other sources, such as publicly available information from social media services, commercially available sources and information from Real Vision Affiliates or business partners.

 **3.1 To provide and manage our services:**  We use the information we collect from and about you to provide our products, services and features to you, including: to process and fulfill your subscription, to send you information about your relationship or transactions with us, to measure and improve those services and features, to allow you to comment on content and participate in online games, contests, promotions or rewards programs, use collaboration tools to share content and collaborate with other users, to provide you with customer support, including online chats, and to respond to inquiries. If you choose to use the collaboration tools, some of your Personal Information may be included in a directory that can be viewed and used by other users of these collaboration tools.

 **3.2 To deliver relevant content and recommendations:**  To make your experience more interesting and personalized, we may use any of the Personal and Other Information we collect to assist us in delivering content on any of our Real Vision Services

 **3.3 To deliver relevant online advertising:**  The Real Vision Services and our service providers may use any of the information we collect from and about you (in certain cases, such as with respect to financial information, only with your express permission) for remarketing purposes to assist us in delivering relevant ads to you when you use the Real Vision Services or another service provided by Real Vision Affiliates. (See Information We Collect, above, for details on the types of information we may use.) As noted above, we may work with third-party online advertising companies and advertisers who help deliver these ads to you. These third parties may collect and use information about your activities on our Real Vision Services and on other websites, and Other Information about you, to limit the online ads you encounter to those we believe are consistent with your interests.

 **3.4 To allow social sharing functionality:**  If you log in with or connect a social media service account with the Real Vision Services, we may use Personal and Other Information to facilitate your sharing of information between the Real Vision Services and your social media service.

 **3.5 To contact you:**  Real Vision and Real Vision Affiliates may periodically send promotional materials, surveys, or notifications related to our products and services. To help make these materials more relevant to you, we may use and combine any of the Personal and Other Information we collect to assist us in sending you these materials. We may also use your information to contact you, including to respond to your comments, inquiries or requests. If you want to stop receiving these materials from us, please follow the instructions in the Choices and Access section below.

 **3.6 To protect the rights of Real Vision and others:**  Real Vision may use your Personal Information as we believe to be necessary or appropriate in order to: (i) protect, enforce, or defend the legal rights, privacy, safety, or property of Real Vision, our Real Vision Affiliates or their employees, agents and contractors (including enforcement of our agreements and our terms of use); (ii) protect the safety, privacy, and security of users of our products and services or members of the public; (iii) protect against fraud or for risk management purposes; (iv) comply with the law or legal process, including laws outside your country of residence; or (v) to respond to requests from public and government authorities including public and government authorities outside your country of residence.

#### 4\. How We Share Your Information 

**4.1 Information Made Public Through Use of Our Services and User Privacy Settings:**  Certain features on the Real Vision Services give you an opportunity to interact with us and others. These may include the collaboration tools, community forums, chats, submitting a letter to the editor, creating community profiles, and rating, tagging and commenting on articles. When you use these features, you should be aware that any information you submit, including your name, user name, location, email address, profile information, picture, likes, status, and comments, may be publicly available to anyone, including other users, search engines, advertisers, third party application developers, and anyone else with access to the Real Vision Services. We are not responsible for any information you choose to submit and make public through these interactive features.

 **4.2 Our Disclosure of Information:**  Real Vision Affiliates may share your Personal Information with one another for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy, including for each company’s marketing purposes. Users who visit Real Vision Affiliates’ services should still refer to their separate privacy policies, which may differ in some respects from this Privacy Policy. Real Vision is the party responsible for the management of the jointly-used Personal Information.

In addition, we may share your Personal Information with non-affiliated third parties when sharing is permitted by you or authorized by this Privacy Policy, including:

 **(a) to manage corporate, third-party, and school subscriptions:**  If your subscription is provided in whole or in part by your employer or other third party, we may notify the provider when you access or use your subscription. If you have a subscription associated with a professor or school, we may notify your professor or school to confirm your subscription, access or use. When providing these notices, we may reveal limited amounts of your Personal Information such as your name or email address.

 **(b) to allow third-party service providers to assist us in providing and managing our services:**  We may make your Personal Information available to certain third-party service providers, such as contractors, agents or sponsors, who help us manage or provide our products and services by, for example: developing or supporting products and features; sending email messages on our behalf; processing payments; fulfilling orders; delivering subscriptions; auditing; processing data or statistics; and serving, customizing or delivering marketing or ads. These outside service providers are required to protect Personal Information entrusted to them and not use it for any other purpose than the specific service they are providing to us.

 **(c) to provide co-branded services and features:**  We may offer co-branded services or features, such as conferences, contests, sweepstakes or other promotions together with a third party (“Co-Branded Services”). These Co-Branded Services may be hosted on the Real Vision Services or on the third party’s service. By virtue of these relationships, we may share the information you submit in connection with the Co-Branded Service with the third party. The third party’s use of your information will be governed by the third party’s privacy policy.

 **(d) to allow social sharing functionality:**  If you log in with or connect a social media service account with the Real Vision Services, we may share your user name, picture, and likes, as well as your activities and comments with other Real Vision Services users and with your friends associated with your social media service. We may also share the same information with the social media service provider. By logging in with or connecting your Real Vision Services account and your social media service, you are authorizing us to share information we collect from and about you with the social media service provider, other users and your friends, and you understand that the social media service’s use of the shared information will be governed by the social media service’s privacy policy. If you do not want your Personal Information shared in this way, please do not connect your social media service account with your Real Vision Services account, and do not participate in social sharing on the Real Vision Services.

 **(e) to protect the rights of Real Vision and others:**  There may be instances when Real Vision may disclose your Personal Information, including situations where we have a good faith belief that such disclosure is necessary in order to: (i) protect, enforce, or defend the legal rights, privacy, safety, or property of Real Vision, our Real Vision Affiliates or their employees, agents and contractors (including enforcement of our agreements and our terms of use); (ii) protect the safety, privacy, and security of users of our products and services or members of the public; (iii) protect against fraud or for risk management purposes; (iv) comply with the law or legal process, including laws outside your country of residence; or (v) to respond to requests from public and government authorities including public and government authorities outside your country of residence, and

 **(f) to complete a merger, sale of assets, or bankruptcy:**  If Real Vision sells all or part of its business or makes a sale or transfer of its assets or is otherwise involved in a merger, bankruptcy, or transfer of all or a material part of its business, Real Vision may transfer your information to the party or parties involved in the transaction as part of that transaction.

Real Vision uses a combination of administrative, technical, personnel and physical measures to safeguard Personal Information in its possession against loss, theft and unauthorized use, disclosure or modification. However, no one can guarantee the complete safety of your information. If you have reason to believe that your interaction with us is no longer secure (for example, if you feel that the security of any account you might have with us has been compromised), please immediately notify us of the problem by contacting our customer service representatives through the messaging functionality made available to you on the Site and through the Services.

**6.1 Your Choices Regarding Our Use and Disclosure of Your Personal Information:**

We give you certain choices regarding our use and disclosure of your Personal Information for marketing purposes.

You may opt-out from receiving electronic communications from us (including surveys or notifications) by changing your account settings through the appropriate link on the website account services page or following the unsubscribe instructions at the bottom of each email.

Please note that there are certain service notifications that you may not opt-out of, such as renewal notices and notifications of changes to Real Vision products and services or policies. If you have installed a mobile app and you wish to stop receiving push notifications, you can change the settings either on your mobile device or through the app.

 **6.2 How to Access, Correct or Update Your Personal Information:**  You can access, review, correct, update, delete or modify your registration or subscription profile information and modify your marketing preferences by contacting our customer service representatives through the messaging functionality made available to you on the Site and through the Services. Most subscribers can also update their Personal Information online by signing on to their accounts and visiting the appropriate account management sections of our websites.

You may also contact Real Vision’s customer service representatives through the messaging functionality made available to you on the Site and through the Services. For your protection, we may only implement requests with respect to the Personal Information associated with the particular email address that you use to send us your request, and we may need to verify your identity before implementing your request. We will try to comply with your request as soon as reasonably practicable.

Please note that we may need to retain certain information for record keeping purposes and/or to complete any transactions that you began prior to requesting such change or deletion (e.g., when you make a purchase or enter a promotion, you may not be able to change or delete the Personal Information provided until after the completion of such purchase or promotion).

 **6.3 Your California Privacy Rights:**  California Law permits our customers who are California residents to request certain information regarding our disclosure of Personal Information to third parties for their own direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please contact our customer service representatives through the messaging functionality made available to you on the Site and through the Services, and provide your name and the address to which you would like us to respond.

#### 7\. Other Important Information

**7.1 Updates to Privacy Policy:**  Real Vision may modify this Privacy Policy. Please look at the Effective Date at the top of this Privacy Policy to see when this Privacy Policy was last revised. Any changes to this Privacy Policy will become effective when we post the revised Privacy Policy on the Real Vision Services. Your use of the Real Vision Services or your provision of Personal Information to us following these changes means that you accept the revised Privacy Policy.

 **7.2 Location of Data:**  Your Personal Information may be stored, transferred to, and processed in any country where we have facilities or in which we engage service providers, and by using our products and services, you consent to the processing and transfer of information to countries outside of your country of residence, including the United States, which may have different data protection rules than in your country.

 **7.3 Data Retention:**  We will retain your Personal Information for the period necessary to fulfill the purposes outlined in this Privacy Policy unless a longer retention period is required or allowed by law.

 **7.4 Collection of Personal Financial Information by a Payment Service:**  In some cases, we may use an unaffiliated payment service to allow you to purchase a product or make payments (“Payment Service”). If you wish to purchase a product or make a payment in such a case, you will be directed to a Payment Service webpage. Any information that you provide to a Payment Service will be subject to the applicable Payment Service’s privacy policy, rather than this Privacy Policy. We have no control over, and are not responsible for, any Payment Service’s use of information collected through any Payment Service.

 **7.5 Linked Services:**  The Real Vision Services may also be linked to sites operated by third parties, and may carry advertisements or offer content, special offers, functionality, games or applications developed and maintained by third parties. Some of these third-party sites may be co-branded with a Real Vision logo, even though they are not operated or maintained by us. Real Vision is not responsible for the privacy practices of any such third parties, and once you leave the Real Vision Services or click an advertisement, or sign up for a special offer, you should check the applicable privacy policy of the other service.

If you have questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact our customer service representatives through the messaging functionality made available to you on the Site and through the Services. We ask that you not disclose any sensitive Personal Information (e.g., social security numbers, information related to racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, sexual orientation, gender status, religion or other beliefs, health, criminal background or trade union membership) when contacting us, as we do not require such information from you.

©Copyright 2019 Real Vision Group SEZC. All rights reserved.
